Guide to the Velvet Underground Collection, 1964-2015.
Velvet Underground Collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Velvet Underground Collection, 1964-2015.
8105
Kugelberg, Johan,
15 cubic feet
Manuscripts, artwork, sound and video recordings, photographs, publications, and ephemera
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection contains manuscripts, artwork, sound and video recordings, photographs, publications, and ephemera related to Andy Warhol and the band The Velvet Underground.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Velvet Underground was an American rock band, active between 1964 and 1973, formed in New York City.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection contains manuscripts, artwork, sound and video recordings, photographs, publications, and ephemera. Manuscripts include holographic notes from Lou Reed and Piero Heliczer, as well as several items in the hand of Velvet Underground guitarist Sterling Morrison, including a set list for a performance at Poor Richard's, in Chicago.
Sound recordings in the archive include six acetate demo records of songs by the band c.1966-69; DAT tapes of unreleased material; first pressings, test pressings, and disc jockey editions of Velvets albums; Sterling Morrison's personal copy of the group's fourth album, Loaded; CDs, singles, EPs, and foreign and domestic bootlegs. Photographs include prints of Velvets performances taken by such contemporary photographers as Paul Morrisey, Billy Name, and Adam Ritchie; as well as vintage contact sheets, press and promo photos, and post-2000 prints in black & white and color.
Posters, flyers and other ephemera include advertisements for appearances of Andy Warhol and the Exploding Plastic Inevitable in New York, the Rhode Island School of Design, and the Factory, as well as films by Warhol and posters for Velvets shows in the US, Prague, and elsewhere; flyers and handbills for Velvets appearances. The collection also includes magazines, press clippings, books, and other publications.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kugelberg, Johan,; Heliczer, Piero.; Morrison, Sterling.; Reed, Lou.; Warhol, Andy, 1928-1987; Velvet Underground (Musical group).
Subjects:
Rock concerts.; Rock music.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Velvet Underground ephemera
Originals
Photocopies and Facsimiles
Series II. Photographs
Loose photographs
Portfolios
Series III. Publications
Series IV. Recordings
Records
10 and 12 inch discs
7 inch discs
Acetates
Digital audio recordings (DAT)
CDs
Officially-released CD boxed sets
Officially-released CDs
Bootleg/unofficially-released CDs
Rare CDRs
Series V. Exhibition and book materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Velvet Underground ephemera, 1954-2009
  - Originals, 1954-2005
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Sterling Morrison's Babylon Theatre Student Identification Card., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Two menus and a business card from Café Bizarre, New York, 1960-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Onondagan." Syracuse University 1963 Yearbook, 1963 (Box 21)
    - "Onondagan." Syracuse University 1964 Yearbook, 1964 (Box 21)
      Page 248 features Lou Reed (center) performing in a band (uncaptioned)
    - Flier for "Caterpillar Changes", February 12, 1965-March 2, 1965; Rubin, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Advertising “Angus MacLise & the Velvet Underground in the Dental Destruction of the Chairs a Mass Concentration Against Furniture by Movies Movies Movie Movies…”
    - Poster for "Caterpillar Changes", 1965-02; Rubin, Barbara (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Autograph note signed to Sterling Morrison, April 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Note written on a folded mailing advertising Piero Heliczers Easter Show at the Bleecker Street Cinema. Reads in full: “dear sterling / hope to have the pleasure /of seeing you / love always / piero”
    - 2 fliers for "Rites of the Dreamweapon", May 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      One is the printed proof with notes in the hand of Angus MacLise. The recto notes revise the information on the flier for MacLise's performances in the New Cinema Festival.
    - New Cinema Festival I - Schedule, November 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Program from the Film-Makers’ Cinematheque, featuring “Rites of the Dreamweapon I: The Tremor Rite” by Angus MacLise and music by the Velvet Underground.
    - Max's Kansas City Cabaret Pass with (Maureen) Moe Tucker's name on it, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Andy Warhol, Up-Tight", February 1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Off0set printed invitation to concert series designed by Paul Morrissey. With text on reverse in the hand of John Cale: "The Perfect Perf"
    - "Spring is a New Beginning." New York: Harcourt, Brace and World, Inc. 1963, March 1966; Anglund, Joan Walsh (Box 21)
      Moe Tucker's copy with her handwriting on front page. Given to attendants at opening of Paraphernalia in March of 1966.
    - Handbill for Andy Warhol’s Underground New York (film screening with live performance by the Velvet Underground and Nico) at Scott Hall, Rutgers University., March 9, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      The only known copy.
    - Press release for "The Plastic Inevitable", Spring 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Typescript flier soliciting performers to participate in “The Exploding Plastic Inevitable.” Reads in full: “Andy Warhol, The Velvet Underground and Nico / “The Plastic Inevitable” / Apply to: The Factory, 231 E. 47th St., New York, N.Y.” Only known copy.
    - Silkscreen poster for Velvet Underground at the Trip, May 3, 1966-May 18, 1966 (Mapcase-folder 2)
      The poster uses Roy Lichtenstein's Pop Art Newsweek cover but was not designed by Lichtenstein.
    - Postcard handbill for Andy Warhol and his Plastic Inevitable with the Velvet Underground and Nico & the Mothers at the Fillmore Auditorium, San Francisco, CA, May 27, 1966-May 29, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Handwritten set-list from Poor Richard’s, Chicago, June 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Set list hand-written in red pen in Sterling Morrison’s hand on the verso of a page of stationary from Maxim’s de Paris, a Chicago restaurant.
    - "Pop Goes the Wedding" Press Release, November 20, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      "“Pop Goes the Wedding.” Oak Park, Michigan: New Worlds Inc., Nov. 20, 1966. 5 p. Press release for “the nation’s first mod wedding ceremony” at the Michigan State Fair Grounds/Carnaby Street Fun Festival, Nov. 18-20, 1966."
    - Poster for Andy Warhol and the Velvet Underground at the Carnaby Street Fun Festival - "The Nation's First Mod Wedding", November 20, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      At the Michigan State Fair Grounds
    - Promotional handbill for the Exploding Plastic Inevitable with the Velvet Underground and Nico, November 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Printed on transparent plastic. No venue is listed but booking information is given with addresses in Cambridge, Massachusetts and Cincinnati, Ohio
    - Verve promotional poster for The Velvet Underground & Nico, 1966 (Mapcase-folder 2)
      Includes the phrase "So Far 'Underground,' You Get the Bends!"
    - Clippings of Newspaper Advertisements, Articles and Announcements, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Mainly from the Village Voice.
    - Newspaper ads and clippings, April 1966-May 1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Press release for "Bananas are in season", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      The Velvet Underground and Nico, Verve Records. The only known copy.
    - 3 acetates poster for "The Velvet Underground and the Exploding Plastic Inevitable" March 31-April 1, 1967 at the Rhode Island School of Design, 1967 (Box 23)
      Red, green, and blue.
    - Flyers for shows at the Boston Tea Party, May 26, 1967-December 14, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Flier for Velvet Underground shows at the Retinal Circus, the Electric Circus, and the Vulcan Gas Company, June 1968-January 30, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 4 leaves of photos removed from Andy Warhol's Moderna Museet catalog., Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Sunn Amps in Action: Velvet Underground", Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Promotional flier for Sunn amplifiers
    - Promotional poster for the Velvet Underground on Verve, 1968 (Mapcase-folder 3)
      Released to promote White/Heat
    - Verve records promotional standee for the Velvet Underground, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Blow up of the photo of the band seated on grass. Signed on reverse - "Moe Tucker/My Copy"
    - "Watchtower." Yearbook for 1969 Beverly Hills High School, 1969 (Box 21)
      Pages 72-73 feature two pictures of The Velvet Underground speaking and performing at the high school
    - Sterling Morrison - Set of 3 charge records, 3 bills, and 1 guest check from Max’s Kansas City., June 1, 1969-October 15, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Guest check notes "Sterling Morrison c/o Warhol 231 E. 47th Street, also known as "The Factory"
    - Sterling Morrison - Gulf station and CCNY Student Center receipts signed by Holmes Morrison Jr., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Set of ten bumper stickers for the Velvet Underground., Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Typeface matches that used on the album The Velvet Underground and Nico
    - Poster for the Velvet Underground at Max's Kansas City, June 1970 (Mapcase-folder 2)
    - Postcard to Danny Fields from Lou Reed, December 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Autograph postcard signed to Danny Fields, postmarked Dec. [16?, 1970]. 1 p.
    - Letter from Dave Marsh at Creem Magazine to Danny Fields and "Dead Lie the Velvets Underground" by Lester Bangs, 1971; Marsh, David; Bangs, Lester (Box 1, Folder 13)
      "Typed letter signed (with ms. corrections) from Dave [Marsh] to Danny Fields. [N.d., 1971.] 1 p. Enclosed with a photocopied facsimile of Lester Bangs’ typescript essay “Dead Lie the Velvets Underground” (32 p.)."
    - "The Nice is not Nico but Nico is Nice", August 5, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "The Velvet Underground: A Biography", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      "“Biography: The Velvet Underground.” Promotional text, 2 p. Chicago: Phonogram Inc./Philips/Mercury/Vertigo. Promotional biography issued for the 1974 album 1969: The Velvet Underground Live (here called The Velvet Underground Live—With Lou Reed)."
    - Letter press poetry by Ira Cohen, 1975-1979 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Distributed by Independent Presses of Katmandu. Also contains prints and poster for event showcasing Ira's poetry.
    - Promotional mailing from SZ Press for The Map of Dusk by Angus MacLise and three other publications, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      5 cards in original mailing envelope addressed to Sterling Morrison.
    - Velvet Underground Appreciation Society. General mailing. Stuart, Florida, May 23, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Newsletter including a set sale list, prospectus for What Goes On discography, and subscription information. Addressed to Ira Cohen.
    - Ticket and Original Set-list for Velvet Underground performance at the Hamburg Sporthalle, June 11, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Set list is written on the verso of a photocopied map of Hamburg.
    - 2-part Poster for the Velvet Underground performance at the Hamburg Sporthalle and Die Halle, Berlin, June 11, 1993-June 20, 1993 (Mapcase-folder 3)
    - Poster for the Velvet Underground at Palac Kultury, Prague, June 13, 1993; Cihlar, Michal (Mapcase-folder 3)
    - Poster for Moe Tucker's album Dogs Under Stress, 1994 (Mapcase-folder 3)
    - 3rd LP Promo Sticker From Sterling Collection, Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Beyond Warhol, the Velvet Underground, 'Loaded'", Undated; Fields, Danny (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Galley proof of the article.
    - Poster for the Velvet Underground: Run, Run, Run, Undated (Mapcase-folder 3)
    - Paul Frank for Andy Warhol, 2005 (Mapcase-folder 3)
      Banana-shaped promotional balloon advertising Paul Frank's Warhol themed fashion line.
  - Photocopies and Facsimiles, 2009
    - Photocopies of Business Correspondence and Riders, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Original materials dated 1967-1969
    - Invitation to "The Nation's First Mod Wedding" November 18-20, 1966 (Facsimile), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      At the Michigan State Fair Grounds/Carnaby Street Fun Festival. Laser-printed facsimile.
    - "It's a Nuptial Happening" - Mod Wedding Article, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      "“It’s a Nuptial Happening.” Photocopied article from Chicago’s American, no date onclipping, circa November 1966."
    - Photocopy of Sterling Morrison's handwritten set-list from Poor Richard’s, Chicago, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Set list hand-written in red pen in Morrison’s hand on the verso of a page of stationary from Maxim’s de Paris, a Chicago restaurant.
    - Nico Interview Notes (Photocopy of Typewritten Interview Outline), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Original dated December 17, 1968
    - Reprint of The Velvet Underground poster for a show at the Woodrose Ballroom, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Reprinted by the Velvet Underground Appriciation Society
    - Newspaper ads and clippings (photocopies), 2009 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Handwritten Letter from Nico to Danny Fields, dated January 13, 1972 (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Velvet Underground at the Dom Article (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "The 1966 Night Beat freakout… Andy Warhol, Nico, The Velvet Underground and the Exploding Plastic Inevitable", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Original dated December 4, 1966
    - "The Youngsters, Brooklyn Symphony Orchestra, The Innkeepers, Plus Many More, With The Nightbeat Birds and Exotic Long Hair Freakos Running Among and Crazy at the Fabulous Action House" Flyer (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Elliott Murphy - Intro to the Velvet Underground Live 1969 Album - (Photocopy of Handwritten Original), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Nico, The Gaslight at the Au Go Go - Announcement (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Marked-Up Typescript of "Dead Lie The Velvets Underground" by Lester Bangs (Photocopy) and Miniature List of January 14, 1966 Articles, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "How Angus Maclise Left The Velvets and Died of the Bends" by John McWhinnie. Lester Bangs Cover, 2009; McWhinnie, John; Bangs, Lester (Box 2, Folder 17)
      “How Angus MacLise Left the Velvets and Died of the Bends.” Computer-printed typescript text, 1 p. With accompanying computer-printed facsimile of the cover page to “Dead Lie the Velvets Underground!” by Lester Bangs.
    - "Authentication of the Accident" by Jean-Jacques Lebel - Page One Photocopy, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Leonard Cohen Quote about Nico, September 4, 1968 (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Comments by Alain Jouffroy - Page One(Photocopy), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Jonathan Richman, Lyrics to "Velvet Underground" (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Nico: The Marble Index (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "A child is born on that day…" Sri Yukteswar Quote (Photocopy), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Photocopies of newspaper ads and articles, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Photocopy of a form filled out by Barbara Rudin for the Film makes Coop, May 1966 and a letter from Barbara Rubin to Jonas Mekas, January 1966, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1966-2007
  - Loose Photographs, 1966-2007
    - Mod Wedding Photos, November 18, 1966-November 20, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Vintage b&w prints from the Carnaby Street Fun Festival at the Michigan State Fair Grounds, including “The Nation’s First Mod Wedding.”
    - White Light/White Heat Mechanical, 1967; Name, Billy (Box 3, Folder 2)
      A still from Andy Warhol’s film "My Hustler" used as the cover image for White Light/White Heat. On the album, the image of a tattooed bicep is printed in black ink on a black background.
    - Promotional Photos for MGM/Verve, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Photograph of the Velvet Underground performing live, December 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Unidentified photographer. Black and white print with stamp of the Sterling Morrison Archive on verso. With accompanying statement of provenance signed by Jeff Gold/Recordmecca.
    - 2 cut outs of Band. 3 prints of Velvet Underground with Nico., 1967; Morrisey, Paul (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Collage components from image shoot for Velvet Underground and Nico promo.
    - 6 envelopes of photos - Lisa Law, Rejects, 2006-2007; Law, Lisa (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 6 envelopes of photos - Doug Yule, Fred McDarrah, 2006-2007; Yule, Doug; McDarrah, Fred (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 5 envelopes of photos - Adam Ritchie, Paul Morrisey, Jonathan, Connie [Radulovitch], 2006-2007; Ritchie, Adam; Morrisey, Paul; Radulovitch, Conniw (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 2 color slides of the Velvet Underground and Nico in Connecticut, 1966, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Unidentified photographer. For prints from this same session see Portfolio 2 in Box 16, and Box 17, Folder 3
    - Color positives of the Velvet Underground and Nico performing at the Dom., April 1966; Morrisey, Paul (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Paul Morrissey. One strip, three color positives.
    - Color slide of the Velvet Underground and Nico performing at the Dom., Undated; Morrisey, Paul (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Vintage black and white negatives of images of the Velvet Underground, 1969-1970; Yule, Doug (Box 3, Folder 9)
      25 strips, 141 images.
    - Vintage color negatives of the Velvet Underground with black and white contact sheets., 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Unidentified photographer. 7 strips. For images from these negatives see Portfolio 2 in Box 16.
    - Several B&w prints of the Velvet Underground during the shooting of the film Venus in Furs, December 1965, March 18, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 17, Folder 2)
      One is signed on verso by Ritchie.
    - Close-up photograph of Moe Tucker from the shooting of the film Venus in Furs, December 1965, 2009; Ritchie, Adam (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Signed on the verso by Ritchie. Printed on p. 27 of The Velvet Underground: New York Art.
    - Multiple B&w prints of the Velvet Underground performing at Café Bizarre, December 1965, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - B&w print of the Velvet Underground performing at the Film-Maker's Cinematheque, February 8-13, 1966, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Color print of Lou Reed at the University of Maryland, Baltimore Campus, September. 1969, 2006-2007; Radulavotich, Connie (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Numbered on verso “I/V.”
    - Color print of the Velvet Underground performing at the New York Society for Clinical Psychiatry dinner at the Delmonico Hotel, January 13, 1966, 2006-2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Inscribed on verso: “For Johan / Adam Ritchie / 22 Dec 2008”
    - Color print of the Velvet Underground performing at the New York Society for Clinical Psychiatry dinner at the Delmonico Hotel, January 13, 1966, 2006-2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Inscribed on verso: “For Johan / Adam Ritchie Dec. 22nd 2008”.
    - Color print of the Velvet Underground and Nico performing, with slide projection of Gerard Malanga and an unidentified woman visible on the wall behind the stage, ca. 1965-1966, 2006-2007 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Color print of the Velvet Underground with Nico taken in Connecticut, Summer 1966, 2006-2007 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Portfolios, 1966-2007
    - Photograph of the Velvet Underground and Nico., 1966 (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 1)
      Image from the photo session for the cover image to the “All Tomorrow’s Parties” 7”.
    - Black and White print of Velvet Underground without Nico, 1966-1967 (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 1)
      All but Tucker are in sunglasses. Nico is not pictured in this print, but appears in other images from this session. This print was used as the mechanical for the cover of Up-Tight by Victor Bockris and Gerard Malanga.
    - Individual photographs of Sterling Morrison (2), Doug Yule, Maureen Tucker, Lou Reed, 1970, Undated; Hall, Henri Ter (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 1)
    - 40 black and white prints from Café Bizarre, December 1965, 2006-2007 (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 1)
      Includes Edie Sedwick, Andy Warhol.
    - 3 black and white prints of members of the Velvet Underground with Andy Warhol, Undated (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 1)
    - Color prints of the Velvet Underground and Nico performing at the Dom., April 1966; Morrissey, Paul (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
      One was used as the cover image for The Velvet Underground: New York Art.
    - Multiple B&w prints of the Velvet Underground during the shooting of the film Venus in Furs, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Multiple color prints of the Factory/Velvet Underground at the New York Society for Clinical Psychiatry dinner at the Delmonico Hotel, January 13, 1966, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Multiple B&w print of the Velvet Underground at the New York Society for Clinical Psychiatry dinner at the Delmonico Hotel, January 13, 1966, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Multiple B&w prints of the Velvet Underground performing at Café Bizarre, December 1965, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Multiple B&w prints of the Velvet Underground performing at the Film-Maker's Cinematheque, February 8-13, 1966, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Multiple color prints of the Velvet Underground at the Film-Makers Cinematheque, February 8-13, 1966, 2007; Ritchie, Adam (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - 3 color prints of Velvet Underground with Nico in Connecticut, 1966, 2006-2007 (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
      Two group photos and one with Nico alone. See Box 17, Folder 3 for another image from this session.
    - RCA promotional photo of Lou Reed, 1970-1979 (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Vintage contact sheets of images for Verve WhiteLight/White Heat promo, 1968 (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
    - Two faded color prints of the Velvet Underground without Nico, Undated (Box 16, Volume Portfolio 2)
      Taken around the time of the release of The Velvet Underground.
- Publications, 1964-2007
  Arranged alphabetically by title of publication.
  - Newspapers, magazines, and other publications, 1966-2009
    - Aloha, February 11, 1972-February 25, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Issue 21
    - Another Magazine, Winter 2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - An Other Man, September 2009-December 2009 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Issue 9
      Two copies
    - Arthur, January 2003 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Art in America, May 1967-June 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Arts Canada, February 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Issue 105
    - Baby Baby Baby, June 2005-September 2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Issue 3
    - The Beat [Excerpt], May 28, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Berkeley Tribe, November 21, 1969-November 28, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Vol. 1, No. 20
    - Canyon Cinema News, May 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Cavalier, October 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Vol. 17, No. 12
    - Celeste, June 2005-September 2005 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Issue 18
    - Charlotte Focus, October, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Vol 2., No. 1
    - Circus, September 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Circus, June 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Vol. 4, No. 7
    - Coast FM and Fine Arts (Partial), September 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      “The Velvet Underground: Music to Watch Warhol By” by James Michael Martin. Vintage photocopied clipping from the Sept. 1969 issue of Coast FM & Fine Arts.
    - Coast FM and Fine Arts, May 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      The Velvet Underground's Lou Reed
    - Crawdaddy, June 1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Issue 16
      Two copies.
    - Crawdaddy, August 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Issue 17
    - Crawdaddy, June 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      issue 23
    - Crawdaddy, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Vol. IV, No. 4, Section 2
    - Creem, March 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Creem, November 1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)